I guess we're ready to do counseling up
我想我们已准备好做好咨询了
here because I've got Kleenexes right
因为我有正确的面巾纸
here behind that pulpit there we go
我们去那里讲坛后面
we're gonna go without PowerPoint again
我们要去没有再次的PowerPoint
just so I can really concentrate on the
所以我真的可以专注于
outline and not get distracted by slides
大纲，不要被幻灯片分心
so a lot to cover and we're gonna dig in
所以要做很多事情，我们要深入挖掘
now notice in your outline the title is
现在在你的大纲中注意标题是
husband's and then biblical manhood so
丈夫的，然后是圣经的男子气概
obviously the two things overlap so
显然这两件事重叠如此
we're gonna be starting off just talking
我们要在出发只谈
about what does it mean to be a man and
关于成为一个男人和女人意味着什么
that can be really difficult in our
这对我们来说真的很难
culture to define my kids gave me a
文化定义我的孩子给了我一个
birthday card one time and the birthday
生日贺卡一次和生日
card had a bunch of tattoos in it rubble
卡片上有一堆纹身瓦砾
and tattoos and it said what's a real
和纹身，它说什么是真实的
man and one of the tattoos was a real
男人和其中一个纹身是真实的
man rides a Harley and well That's not
男人骑着哈利，那不是
me so I can't wear that tattoo another
我所以我不能再戴那个纹身了
one was real men love hardware stores
一个是真正的男人喜欢五金店
all the men say Amen right so I thought
所有的人都说阿门是对的，所以我想
well that one does fit I really do like
好吧，一个人确实适合我真的喜欢
hardware stores I don't know what it is
五金店我不知道它是什么
about the nuts and bolts and all that
关于螺母和螺栓等等
kind of stuff but just looking it up the
样的东西，但只是看它了
tools and so that's the tattoo I rubbed
工具，这就是我擦过的纹身
on my arm and we're on my birthday real
在我的手臂上， 我们生日快乐
men love hardware stores I already told
男人喜欢我已经告诉过的五金店
you that from my cultural background if
你是我的文化背景，如果
you didn't carry a pocketknife you're
你没带小折刀
not a real man what what defines a man
不是真正的男人是什么定义了一个男人
what is it that makes someone a man is
什么使某人成为一个男人
it getting married and just think about
它结婚，只是想想
how difficult this isn't our culture
这不是我们的文化有多难
went how do we define manhood when do
我们如何定义男子气概何时这样做
you become a man is it marriage that all
你成为一个男人就是这样的婚姻
you know you said I do and boom you're
你知道你说我做了， 你就是这样
now you're a man because you got married
现在你是男人，因为你结婚了
well I've counseled guys that were
好吧，我已经劝过那些人
married with three children and I
我和三个孩子结婚了
actually said the one guy I wish you
实际上是说我希望你的那个人
wouldn't have gotten married
不会结婚的
he was not acting very responsible we
他对我们的行为不是很负责任
call it the Peter Pan syndrome he didn't
称之为彼得潘综合症他没有
want to grow up he just wanted to be a
想要长大，他只想成为一名
boy his whole life and he wasn't a
男孩， 他的一生，他不是一个
father he was more of like just like a
父亲他更像是一个
grown-up boy with his sons and he really
成年男孩与他的儿子和他真的
wasn't disciple
不是门徒
getting married doesn't necessarily make
结婚并不一定
someone a man so for years I searched
有人一个人这么多年我搜索
around for a definition of manhood and
周围 的男子气概和男子气概 的定义
finally came across in the book
终于在书中遇到了
recovering biblical manhood and
恢复圣经的男子气概
womanhood a great definition of manhood
女性是男子气概的一个伟大定义
by John Piper and that's where we're
约翰派珀，这就是我们所在的地方
going to start it's right there under
要开始它就在那里
the introduction and it's gonna feel
引进和它的会觉得
like wow are we ever going to get out of
像哇我们永远都会离开
the introduction so just bear with me
介绍所以只是忍受我
let's talk about this this statement of
让我们来谈谈这个的这个说法
manhood and it's gonna overlap with what
男子气概，它会与什么重叠
does it mean to be a husband so john
意思是丈夫因此，约翰
piper and wayne grudem's say this at the
piper和Wayne grudem的说法是这样的
heart of mature masculinity so it's
成熟男性气质的核心所以它是
different than masculinity mature
不同于男性气概成熟
masculinity at the heart of mature
男性气质是成熟的核心
masculinity is a sense of benevolent so
男性气质是一种仁慈的感觉
it's loving benevolent responsibility to
它是慈爱的仁慈责任
lead you can be a leader that's not
领导你可以成为一个不是的领导者
benevolent right so you can be a leader
仁慈的， 所以你可以成为领导者
that's domineering this is benevolent
那是霸气，这是仁慈的
leadership provide for benevolent
领导提供仁慈
providing and protect women in ways
以某种方式提供和保护妇女
appropriate to man's differing
适合男人的不同
relationships to lead provide for and
领导关系提供和
protect and that really gets at the core
保护，真正成为核心
of what manhood is and I believe you can
什么是男子气概，我相信你可以
prove this biblically ladies you it's
证明这是圣经女士你的意思
much easier for women you have whole
对于你拥有整体的女性来说更容易
passages like proverbs 31 that chapter
像箴言那样的章节那一章
that you love to hate right and but you
你又爱又恨权 ，但你
have a whole chapter that says here's a
有一整章说这里是一个
godly woman that you can be emulating
你可以效仿的敬虔女人
and aim for it but we don't have one
并以此为目标， 但我们没有
chapter in Scripture that defines
圣经中定义的章节
manhood so what do we do well here's
男子气概所以我们在这里做得很好
what we do we look at the example of the
我们做什么我们看看的例子
man the most important man that
那个人最重要的人
lived on the planet and that's our
住在这个星球上，这就是我们的
savior the Lord Jesus Christ and we ask
救主耶稣基督，我们问
ourselves what was the essence of who he
我们自己是谁的本质是什么
was as a man and this definition fits
作为一个男人，这个定义适合
well loving leadership loving provision
热爱领导的爱心提供
loving protection he gave his life for
热爱保护他为生命付出了生命
his flock he leads his flock he led his
他带领他的羊群带领着他的羊群
flock he provides for his flock so I'm
他为羊群提供了羊群，所以我
gonna start with that idea of what we're
要开始 的我们是什么想法
aiming for is christ-like leadership
瞄准的是基督式的领导力
Christ is modeling for us leading
基督正在为我们领导建模
providing for and protecting now I have
我现在提供和保护
a lot of object lessons with me for this
我有很多对象课程
this one and we'll just have to take
这一个，我们只需要采取
these as it goes but I have three
这些， 但我有三个
pictures here hope the lights don't
这里的照片希望灯不亮
shine off too much but I've kept these
闪耀太多，但我保留了这些
in my office for years to remind me what
在我的办公室多年来提醒我什么
my responsibility is as a shepherd and
我的责任是作为一个牧羊人和
this pic this picture is picturing a
这张照片是这张照片
shepherd as a leader I'll show you the
牧羊人作为领导我会告诉你
next one this one is picturing the
下一个这个人是想象的
shepherd as a protector and then the
牧羊人作为保护者，然后是
next one is picturing a shepherd as one
下一个是将牧羊人描绘成一个
who cares for the flock and I've had
我关心羊群的人
those hanging on my office wall for
那些挂在我办公室墙上的人
years just to keep in front of me my
几年只是为了保持在我面前
responsibility both with the church and
对教会和教会都负有责任
at home and I'm gonna go back through
在家里，我要回去了
these in just a moment but let me just
这些只是片刻，但让我公正
make a comment about the idea of
对...的想法发表评论
shepherding wouldn't it go a long way if
如果，牧养不会走很长的路
we could get engrained into the men that
我们可以深深扎根于那些男人身上
we're disciple is really about
我们的门徒真的很关心
shepherding we're teaching our men to be
牧养我们教导我们的人
the Shepherd's of their flock of their
他们的羊群中 的牧羊人
home I want to teach the men that I'm
我想告诉那些我是男人的家
mentoring to be the Shepherd of their
指导成为他们的牧羊人
home I lead the men's ministries at our
我领导男人的事工
church up and act in Crown Valley
教堂和皇冠谷的行为
Community Church and one of our goals in
社区教会和我们的目标之一
our church is that every man would be
我们的教会就是每个人都会
elder qualified that's one of the
老人认为这是其中之一
ambitions that we've put out in front of
我们在前面提出的雄心壮志
us for the men's ministries at our
我们为我们的男人事工
church that we're aiming for
我们正在瞄准教堂
first Timothy three that every man would
第一个提摩太三，每个人都会
meet the qualifications of an elder
符合老人的资格
every man be elder qualified those
每个人都是老年人
character traits and learned to be a
性格特征和学会成为一个
shepherd in their homes let's just walk
牧羊人在他们的家中让我们走路
back through these for a moment and
回到通过这些了一会儿，
think about them in a little more detail
想想他们在更详细 一点
loving leadership there's gonna be a
爱的领导，那将是一个
whole section a little bit later in the
整整一段稍后
outline ten sub points of what it means
概述了十个子要点
to be a leader that I got from John
成为我从约翰那里得到的领导者
Piper so I'm gonna skip over that one
派珀所以我要跳过那一个
for just a moment providing for this
暂时提供这个
provision both as a pastor the Shepherd
作为牧羊人的牧师
and then in home you just see biblically
然后在家里你只是看到圣经
reinforced with the idea that the the
的想法加强了对
man in the home is to be the main
在家里的人是主要的
provider for the family and you can go
家庭的提供者，你可以去
to all kinds of passages but the one
各种各样的段落，但一个
that I would cite there is that God is
我会引用上帝的意思
gave Adam the responsibility of being
让亚当有责任成为
the one for tilling the garden in
一个用于耕种花园的
Genesis 2 and then protection in ways
创世纪2然后保护方式
loving protection in ways that are
以各种方式保护自己
appropriate to a man's differing
适合男人的不同
relationships and let's go into a little
关系，让我们进入一点点
more detail and talk about a christ-like
更多细节，谈论基督般的
husband and you can define this two
老公，你可以定义这两个
different ways lead provide for and
领导提供的不同方式和
protect or three L's lover learner and
保护或三个L's 爱人学习者和
servant leaders so the rest of the
仆人领袖所以其余的
outline is going to revolve around these
大纲将围绕这些展开
three L's lover learner and servant
三个爱人的学习者和仆人
leader so let's think about what
领导所以让我们考虑一下
Ephesians 5 means when it says husbands
以弗所书5章的意思是说丈夫
love your wives and notice the next two
爱你的妻子，注意接下来的两个
words because guys this gives us a model
因为这些人给了我们一个模型
that is really amazing to live up to
辜负真的很棒
just as Christ also loved the church and
正如基督也喜爱教会和教会一样
gave himself up for her just as Christ
像基督一样为自己献身
loved the church and gave himself up for
爱教会，并为自己做好准备
her that means we're gonna have to
她意味着我们必须这样做
define love here a little bit and just
在这里定义爱一点点
slow down and think about what is love
慢下来，想想什么是爱情
and what isn't love our culture is
什么不爱我们的文化
confused on the idea of love and here's
困惑于爱和这里的想法
some of the things that I wrote down of
一些我写下来的东西
what it means to love someone obviously
明显地爱一个人意味着什么
in our culture popular views it's a
在我们的文化中，流行的观点是一个
feeling that you have in our culture
感觉你在我们的文化中
it's sexual and we use the term make
它是性的，我们使用术语make
love
爱
most often I would say it's actually
通常我会说它实际上是
making lust not making love it's
使欲望不做爱它
something you fall into which implies
你陷入其中暗示的东西
you can fall out of it and it's romantic
你可以脱离它，它是浪漫的
it has to do and nothing wrong with this
它必须做，而且没有错
right ladies you like the romance idea
合适的女士们，你喜欢浪漫的想法
flowers and atmosphere and all of those
鲜花和气氛以及所有这些
things as part of love but a biblical
作为爱的一部分，但圣经的东西
view of love is much Meteor and I'm
爱的观点是很多流星，而我
gonna give you a definition of what I
给你一个我的定义
think agape love is about and I'm sure
认为agape爱是关于我的确定
you've heard sermons on agape love first
你 第一次 听到关于神的爱说教
Corinthians 13 that would be the idea
哥林多前书13就是这个主意
behind the Ephesians 5 that says
在以弗所书5后面说
husbands love your wives just as Christ
丈夫 像基督一样爱你的妻子
also loved the church its agape love
也喜欢教会的爱情
here's a definition I've used for years
这是我多年来一直使用的定义
of what agape love is and it got tweaked
agape爱是什么，它被调整了
a little bit in recent years by John
近年来约翰一点点
Piper so you're gonna hear a little bit
派珀所以你会听到一点点
of John Piper influence in this
在这个约翰·派博影响力
definition of love if you're familiar
如果你熟悉的话，爱的定义
with him self sacrificial giving for the
与他自己牺牲给予了
betterment of another then I'm gonna add
改善另一个，然后我会补充
another part in just a moment self
只是片刻的另一部分自我
sacrificial giving for the betterment of
为了改善而牺牲
another and then here's the Piper
另一个然后是Piper
influence that leads to your true
影响导致你的真实
happiness self sacrificial giving for
幸福的自我牺牲
the betterment of another that leads to
另一个导致的改善
your true happiness finding fulfillment
你真正的快乐找到满足感
in serving others finding satisfaction
在服务他人寻求满足
in giving yourself for others finding
为自己寻找其他人
true happiness in loving others self
爱自己的真正幸福
sacrificial giving that seeks for the
牺牲奉献，力求为
betterment of another's that leads to
改善导致的另一个人
your true happiness now we don't have
你现在没有真正的幸福
time to go through all of these sub
是时候经历所有这些潜艇了
points but what I'm gonna do is just
要点， 但我要做的只是
I've gone through and I've picked out
我已经走了，我已经选中了
ones that I want to comment on in a
那些我想在评论中评论的
little more detail what what
更多细节是什么
this biblical love so I have all kinds
这种圣经的爱，所以我有各种各样的
of sub points here what does it mean as
这里的子要点是什么意思
Christ loved the church is we're seeking
我们正在寻求基督爱教会
to be biblical men to lead provide for
要成为圣经中的男人
and protect it is initiatory this type
保护它是这种类型的初始化
of love takes the initiative servants
爱是主动的仆人
take the initiative first John 4:19 says
主动第一约翰一书4:19说：
we love because He first loved us but
我们爱，因为他首先爱我们但是
I'd like to go to another passage that's
我想转到另一个通道这
not in your notes look at mark chapter
不在你的笔记中看标记章节
10 mark chapter 10 and let's turn there
10标记第10章，让我们转向那里
this is a great passage to use when
这是一个很好的通道
we're teaching men what is biblical
我们在教男人什么是圣经
manhood verses 44 and 45 the Lord's
男人的第44和45节是耶和华的
disciples were in a debate with one
门徒与一个人进行辩论
another who was the greatest who is
另一位最伟大的人
going to get to sit in the seat of Honor
要坐在 荣誉 的座位上
and the Lord gives them a talk about
耶和华赐给他们讲话
servanthood mark 10 44 and 45 so men
仆人马克10 44和45所以男人
part of the principle here would be this
这里的部分原则就是这个
is not about grappling my way to be
不是为了挣扎我的方式
treated as the king of my home this is
被视为我家的王者
the servant attitude of tintin mark 10
丁丁标记10的仆人态度
44 and 45 even our Lord says whoever
44和45 甚至我们的主也说谁
wishes to be first among you shall be
希望成为你的第一人
slave of all even for even the Son of
所有人的奴隶，即使是儿子也是如此
Man our Lord did not come to be served
我们的主没有来接待我
but to serve and to give his life a
但要为他的生活服务并付出生命
ransom for many
许多人的赎金
the idea that servants when they see
他们看到仆人的想法
needs take the initiative to meet those
需要主动去满足那些
needs and there's all kinds of other
需要和其他各种各样的
principles about love in this it's
关于爱情在这个原则是
sacrificial it's humble etc we are to be
牺牲它谦卑等我们将成为
the models of servant leadership in our
我们的仆人式领导模式
homes go to point D in your notes I'm
在我的笔记中，房屋转到D点
going to skip over the next few so on
如此继续跳过接下来的几个
the next page this type of love is
下一页这种爱是
volitional the Lord chooses to love us
主选择爱我们的意志
in spite of our unloved leanness
尽管我们不喜欢精益求精
volitional love you did not choose me
意志爱你没有选择我
but I chose you and appointed you that
但是我选择了你并指定了你
you should go and bear fruit etc the
你应该去和见效等的
next one is one that we have to stop and
下一个是我们必须停下来的
think about because it's worded a little
想想因为它的措辞有点
bit strangely instead of unconditional
有点奇怪而不是无条件
love contre conditional love now there's
爱 现在有条件的爱
many things about the idea of
很多关于这个想法的 事情
unconditional love that our culture
无条件地爱我们的文化
teaches that are quite attractive I just
教我非常有吸引力
love you and I accept you but part of
爱你，我接受你，但一部分
the problem that I would have with the
我会遇到 的问题
idea of unconditional love instead of
无条件的爱而不是无条件的想法
contra conditional and I'll explain
有条件的，我会解释
contra conditional in just a moment
只是片刻的条件
unconditional love traditionally also
传统上也是无条件的爱
teaches this just accept me the way I am
教这只是接受我我的方式
and don't put any pressure on me to
并且不要对我施加任何压力
change now that if that's what we mean
现在改变，如果这就是我们的意思
by unconditional love that is not a
通过无条件的爱而不是
biblical view of love Christ loves us
圣经对爱的看法基督爱我们
and accepts us but with an agenda to
并接受我们， 但有议程
change us into Christlikeness he accepts
把我们变成他所接受的基督化
me where I am and then is lovingly
我在那里，然后是含情脉脉
helping me grow to be better than I was
帮助我成长得比我好
because I'm learning to be more like my
因为我正在学习更像我的
Savior contra conditional meaning it's
救主反对条件意味着它
the opposite opposing conditional
相反的反对条件
against conditional not unconditional
有条件的不是无条件的
better than unconditional because Romans
因为罗马人比无条件更好
5:8 says God demonstrates his own love
5：8说上帝表明了自己的爱
toward us while we were sinners Christ
当我们是罪人基督的时候，对着我们
died for us and then he helps us grow
为我们而死，然后他帮助我们成长
and change in Christ's likeness wouldn't
在基督的肖像 变化不会
be very loving parent parenting would it
非常爱父母养育它
to say I love you unconditionally
说我无条件地爱你
meaning I just accept you as you are son
我只是接受你，因为你是儿子
and I'm never gonna put any pressure on
我永远不会施加任何压力
you to change and that's not very loving
你要改变，那不是很有爱心
parenting I actually I need my wife to
养育我其实我需要我的妻子
lovingly help me grow and change in
亲切地帮助我成长和改变
Christ's likeness and she's not here to
基督的样式，她不在这里
defend herself but I would say the same
保卫自己，但我会说同样的
about her
关于她
that she needs my loving grace and mercy
她需要我慈爱的恩典和怜悯
and speaking truth into her life to help
并将真相讲述到她的生活中来帮助
her grow and change in Christ's likeness
她在基督的形象中 成长和改变
you can read the rest but let's skip
你可以阅读其余内容，但让我们跳过
down to practical this love is practical
实用这种爱是实用的
love it shows itself first John 3:18
爱它首先显示约翰福音3:18
little children let us not love with
小孩子让我们不爱
words but in deed and in truth I heard a
言语，但事实上，我听到了一个
funny story one time about a man who was
关于一个男人的有趣故事
trying to be romantic and express his
试图浪漫并表达他的观点
deep deep love for his wife and he said
深深地爱着他的妻子，他说
honey I love you with all my heart and I
亲爱的，我爱你用我所有的心脏和我
would die for you and she looked at him
会为你而死 ，她看着他
and said you don't have to die for me
并说你不必为我而死
just do the dishes what would your wife
只是做你的妻子会做什么菜
think men would show love to her what
以为男人会献爱心对她意味着什么
are the things that say I love you to
是说我爱你的事情
her learning to love in a practical way
她以实际的方式学会了爱
and then there's a whole list there of
然后有一个完整的清单
actual ways to show love telling her the
表达爱情的实际方式告诉她
wife one time said you never tell me you
妻子有一次说你永远不会告诉我你
love me anymore well I told you when we
我爱你了，我告诉你的时候
got married and if I changed my mind I
结婚，如果我改变主意，我
would have told you that said all kinds
会告诉你说各种各样的
of ways to show love telling her
如何表达爱情告诉她
appreciating her I think of a lot of
欣赏她， 我想到了很多
these things they just fall under the
他们只是属于这些东西
category of shepherding and that's why I
牧羊的类别， 这就是我的原因
like these pictures of the shepherds and
像这些牧羊人和牧羊人的照片
keep the Shepherd and keeping it in
保持牧羊人并保持它
front of me because my family is my
在我面前，因为我的家人是我的
chief flock learning to love my family
首席羊群学习爱我家
as if they are my chief flock telling
因为如果他们是我主要的羊群有说服力
her appreciating her making time for her
她欣赏她为她腾出时间
communicating sharing let's just think
沟通分享让我们想一想
about that one for a moment treating her
关于那个片刻对待她
as a complete partner friendship this is
作为一个完整的伙伴友谊，这是
not about superiority inferiority etc
不是关于优越劣势等
this is learning to treat your spouse as
这是学会对待你的配偶
if
如果
she is a complete partner promoting her
她是推销她的完整伙伴
growth and development asking this
增长和发展问这个
question how can I help my wife grow and
问我怎样才能帮助我的妻子成长
flourish and develop her gifts I would
我愿意发展和发展她的礼物
challenge men with do you even know your
挑战男人你甚至知道你的
wife's spiritual gifts and then what can
妻子的精神礼物然后可以
you do to help her really blossom with
你这样做是为了帮助她真正开花
her spiritual gifts that was a lesson
她的精神礼物是一个教训
that I really needed to learn as a
我真的需要学习的
husband was what are my wife's gifts my
老公是我妻子送给我的礼物
mom was a pastor's wife my wife grew up
妈妈是我妻子长大的牧师的妻子
in a strong church with a very strong
在一个非常强大的强大教堂里
pastor's wife and there was a model that
牧师的妻子，并有一个模型，
both my mom gave as a pastor's wife and
我母亲都是牧师的妻子
the pastor's wife that was modeled for
被模仿的牧师的妻子
her in the church where she grew up that
她在她长大， 教会
my wife assumed that if I am NOT that
我的妻子认为如果我不是那个
then I am NOT a good pastor's wife and
那我不是一个好牧师的妻子
we both had to figure that out in the
我们俩都不得不弄明白了
first few years of what does it mean for
最初几年是什么意思 了
my wife to be a good pastor's wife in
我的妻子是一个好牧师的妻子在
the model that my mom modeled and the
我妈妈模仿的模型和
lady that my or the pastor's wife that
女士，我或牧师的妻子
my wife saw the will pastor's wife ran
我的妻子看到遗嘱牧师的妻子跑了
all the women's ministries in the church
教会中所有妇女的事工
she always was teaching teaching
她一直在教学
something in the church well my wife
教堂里的东西和我老婆的关系
would tell you that is not her spiritual
会告诉你那不是她的精神
giftedness but her spiritual giftedness
天赋， 但她的精神天赋
as we learned through the years was
正如我们多年来所了解的那样
definitely in the area of hospitality
绝对是在热情好客的领域
and as she learned to develop that whole
当她学会发展这整体时
giftedness of hospitality she just
她只是热情好客的天赋
flourished with her hospitality
她热情好客
promoting her growth and development
促进她的成长和发展
treating her as a priority another area
将她视为另一个领域的优先事项
that I had to learn was I need to make
我必须学习的是我需要做的
sure that she was in my calendar
确定她在我的日历中
why is everybody else getting in my
为什么其他人都进入我的
calendar but my wife doesn't get in my
日历，但我的妻子没有进入我的
calendar and learning to put aside
日历和学习放在一边
regular time to protect my relationship
定期保护我的关系
with with her look at Jay I think that's
和她一起看杰伊，我想是的
a really interesting point we're to love
我们要爱的一个非常有趣的观点
our wives as you love yourself as you
我们的妻子就像你爱自己一样
love yourself
爱自己
Ephesians 5 says this so husband's ought
以弗所书5章说这是丈夫应该的
also to love their own
也爱自己
wives interesting phrase as their own
妻子有趣的短语作为自己的
bodies every time I read this I mean
每次我读这个都是我的意思
literally every time I read this I get
从字面上看，每次我读到这个，我都会得到
challenged by this love my wife as if
受到这种爱的挑战我的妻子仿佛
she is part of my own body well that's
她是我自己身体的一部分
exactly what Genesis 2 says she is she
正是Genesis2所说的她就是她
is one flesh with me now here's the
是一个肉体和我现在这里的
challenging question for me how much
挑战性的问题对我来说有多大
time do I give myself versus how much
我给自己的时间与多少
time do I give my wife love her as I
我和妻子一样爱我
love my own body as their own body do I
爱我自己的身体作为我自己的身体
give my wife as much attention as I give
给我的妻子尽可能多的关注
myself and you see the point of the
我和你看到的重点
passage very quickly
通过很快
don't you learning to love your wife as
你不学会爱你的妻子
if she is part of me she's part of your
如果她是我的一部分，她就是你的一部分
body and according to Genesis that she
身体和根据创世纪，她
she is then Ephesians says that this
她是以弗所人说的
includes let's go to that passage
包括让我们去那段话
Ephesians chapter 5 this includes
以弗所书第5章包括
nourishing and cherishing we've got to
滋养和珍惜我们必须
think about this one for a little bit as
想一想这个
we think about what it means to be a
我们考虑成为一个 什么意味着什么
husband Ephesians 5 verse verses 28 and
丈夫以弗所书5节28节和28节
29 and I want to give you a little bit
29，我想给你一 点点
of an idea what did these two words mean
一个想法是什么做了这两个词的意思
nourish and cherished so that we help
滋养和珍惜，以便我们提供帮助
ourselves as husbands here so husband's
我们自己在这里做丈夫的丈夫
ought also to love their own wives as
也应该爱自己的妻子
their own bodies he who loves his own
他们爱自己的自己的身体
wife loves himself for no one ever hated
妻子爱自己，没有人恨过
his own flesh but nourishes and
他自己的肉，但滋养和
cherishes it just as Christ also does
像基督一样珍惜它
the church let's think about this for a
教会让我们考虑一下这个
moment
时刻
nourish it means bring to maturity it's
滋养它意味着它成熟
the same word that is used or to tend to
使用或倾向于使用相同的词
bring to maturity and I'll give you an
带来成熟，我会给你一个
illustration in just a moment it's the
插图只是片刻而已
same word that's used in just one
只用一个的同一个词
chapter over of fathers bring up your
父亲的章节提出你的
children bring them up in the discipline
孩子们把他们带入纪律
and instruction of the Lord it's the
这是主的指示
same word bring them up think of plants
同一个词让他们想起植物
tending plants and I try to be a
抚育植物，我努力成为一个
or up in Acton but it's really hard to
或者在Acton，但这真的很难
be a gardener vegetable gardener in the
做一名园丁蔬菜园丁
desert I've found over the last seven
沙漠我在过去七年里找到了
years I'm still working on it at you you
年我还在上你，你
know it's bit when you can't even get
当你甚至无法得到时，知道它有点儿
green beans to grow but I'm still trying
绿豆增长但我还在努力
I'm determined I'm gonna get green beans
我决心要吃青豆
to grow in the desert think of gardening
在沙漠中成长想到园艺
I've been put in all kinds of work into
我已经参加了各种各样的工作
trying to get that soil healthy and when
试图让土壤健康，何时
those plants start to grow
那些植物开始生长
you better believe on being attentive
你最好相信在被细心
because it's hard enough to even get to
因为它甚至难以达到
seed the germinate and if that thing
种子萌发，如果那东西
grows I'm gonna be putting a lot of
我会增加很多
attention into it to try to keep it
注意它，试图保持它
healthy and if we'd start getting in
健康，如果我们开始进入
there I'm paying attention and I'm
在那里，我正在关注，我
trying to get rid of the weeds and I'm
试图摆脱杂草，我
making sure that I'm watering it
确保我正在浇水
properly
正确
that's this word cultivate tend we've
这就是我们所培养的这个词
lost in the United States the idea look
迷失在美国的想法看
it up do the study on it men what does
它对男人的研究做了什么呢
it mean to be a husband husband now I'm
现在我是丈夫的丈夫
not going to make the I don't want to
不会让我不想
have our minds go to the illustration
我们的想法去图解
but it is a really natural connection to
但这是一个非常自然的联系
think of someone going to school to
想到有人去上学
study animal husbandry and you're
研究畜牧业，你
learning to care and nurture a flock
学会关心和养育羊群
we've really lost that idea of what does
我们真的失去了那个想法
it mean to be a husband to nourish and
它意味着要成为一个养育和养育的丈夫
then to cherish it's nothing difficult
然后珍惜它并不困难
about this word at all it means to hug
关于这个词，它意味着拥抱
thank you ladies it means to warm
谢谢女士，这意味着温暖
nourish and cherish so husbands what are
滋养和珍惜丈夫是什么
we supposed to do we're supposed to
我们应该这样做
nourish and cherish our wives and it's
滋养和珍惜我们的妻子
incredible to think of this just as
让人难以想象的是这只是作为
Christ also does the church it includes
基督也在做它所包含的教会
nourishing and cherishing now that leads
现在滋养和珍惜导致
us to the second L and as we go through
我们到了第二个L并且我们经历了
this just be thinking to yourself what
这只是在想自己是什么
are the things that you need to be
是你需要做的事情
teaching the men that you influence or
教你影响或影响的男人
what are the things that you need to be
什么是你需要的东西
applying to your own life as I got to
适应我自己的生活
the end of this and reviewing my notes I
结束这个并回顾我的笔记我
thought well there's some things I need
我认为有一些我需要的东西
to go back and review for myself
回去看看自己
the second L a christ-like husband is a
第二个L是一个像基督一样的丈夫
learner christ-like husband is a learner
学习者基督般的丈夫是学习者
famous verse first Peter 3:7 let's go
着名的诗歌第一章彼得前书3：7我们走了
there first Peter 3:7 talk about
有第一彼得3：7谈
controversy here we go first Peter 3:7
在这里我们先争论彼得前书3：7
Hugh husband's likewise live with your
休丈夫同样和你一起生活
wives in an understanding way should I
我应该以理解的方式对待妻子
read it ladies okay thank you as with a
阅读女士好吗谢谢你作为一个
weaker vessel since she is a woman and
因为她是一个女人而且较弱的船只
grant her honor as a fellow heir of the
授予她作为继承人的荣誉
grace of life so that your prayers may
生活的恩典， 以便你的祈祷可能
not be hindered this passage teaches us
不要妨碍这段经文告诉我们
men that we are to be constant learners
男人，我们要成为不断学习的人
when it comes to our wife
说到我们的妻子
now obviously point one says your
现在很明显， 有人说你的
culture says you can't understand a
文化说你无法理解
woman remember the book years ago men
女人多年前记得这本书的男人
are from Mars Women are from Venus we
来自火星女人来自金星我们
would say we're different by design what
可以说，我们通过设计不同的是什么
in the world does this passage mean
这段经文意味着世界
treat her live with her in an
在她身边和她一起生活
understanding way as with a weaker
理解方式与弱者一样
vessel brought an illustration along
船带来了一个插图
another object lesson here I brought a
另一个对象课我带来了一个
vessel with me so here's my vessel all
和我在一起的船只所以这里是我的船只
right and then for the sake of
右，然后着想
illustration
插图
this is also going to be a vessel
这也将成为一艘船
alright so vessel one vessel two what
好吧所以船只一艘船两个什么
does it mean to be a weaker vessel I'd
这是否意味着我是一个较弱的船只
like to present and argue that the idea
喜欢提出并争论这个想法
of weaker vessel does not mean inferior
较弱的船只并不意味着劣质
this ship was made for me by a man at
这艘船是由一名男子在我身上制造的
our church where I pastored in Michigan
我在密歇根州牧养的教堂
as when I was leaving the church he was
就像我离开教堂时一样
retired and this is what he did for a
退休了，这就是他为一个人所做的
hobby he had a six-foot-long aircraft
他有一个六英尺长的飞机
carrier that was actually operational
实际运营的运营商
and had elevators and this guy had a lot
并有电梯，这家伙有很多
of time he built this from a blueprint
他从蓝图中建立了这个时间
he got the blueprints of the actual ship
他得到了实际船的蓝图
of this is called the Fair American was
这被称为美国公平
a Revolutionary War ship and you can
一艘革命战舰，你可以
look up its history the battles that it
查看它的历史战争吧
was in during the Revolutionary War he
他在革命战争期间
built it from the hall up from the
从大厅建起来的
blueprints all hand nailed planks down
蓝图全部用手钉下木板
here you could look at it afterwards
在这里你可以看看它
there's all little hand nails down
所有的小指甲都掉了下来
through here all hand-tied rigging
通过这里所有手工绑定的索具
actually it's quite valuable and I try
实际上这很有价值，我试试
to be really careful with it and protect
要非常小心并保护
it since it's fragile it's a vessel but
因为它很脆弱所以它是一艘船但是
it's actually really valuable weaker
它实际上真的很有价值
does not necessarily mean inferior it
并不一定意味着它逊色
can actually mean superior in value now
实际上现在意味着更高的价值
men the way I think of us is we're
男人，我想到我们的方式就是我们
vessels too but we're kind of like this
船也是，但我们有点像这样
ladies are like this to be treated with
女士们都喜欢这样待
great care and respect as as the way
非常谨慎和尊重
that God designed them so weaker vessel
上帝设计他们如此虚弱的船只
in first Peter 3:7 does not mean
在彼得前书3：7并不意味着
inferior in any way ladies you're
以任何方式低于女士们
supposed to applaud when I say that
当我这么说时应该鼓掌
thank you
谢谢
weaker does not mean inferior now what
弱者并不意味着现在的劣势
does it mean that a husband is supposed
这是否意味着丈夫应该被认为
to dwell with his wife in an
与妻子住在一起
understanding way obviously that let me
理解方式显然让我
read you one more quote about the weaker
再读一篇关于弱者的报价
vessel I didn't want to skip over this
船我不想跳过这个
this is what one commentator said about
这是一个评论员说，大约
that phrase showing respect for the
该词组示出 了用于相对于
woman as you would a valuable vase
女人，因为你会有一个珍贵的花瓶
showing respect for the woman as you
显示了女人 ，你的尊重
would a valuable vase so we're supposed
我们应该是一个有价值的花瓶
to dwell with our wife in an
与我们的妻子住在一起
understanding way that takes time
理解需要时间的方法
obviously one of the biggest things that
显然是最重要的事情之一
I've needed to learn in life not just
我不仅需要在生活中学习
with my wife but just in life in general
与我的妻子，但在生活中一般
is not everybody processes life the same
不是每个人都一样处理生活
way I do thank the Lord for that we'd
方式我感谢主，因为我们
have a bunch of analytical thinkers
有一堆分析思想家
running around all over the place and
到处乱跑和
that would drive everybody crazy may
这将推动大家疯狂的5月
drive everybody be driving everybody
推动每个人都在开车
else crazy my brain the way I think
我想的方式让我的大脑疯狂
about life I just analyze things to
关于生活我刚刚分析事情
pieces and I'm just thinking through
碎片，我只是在想
details I praise God for that because
细节我赞美上帝，因为
that helps me think about the details of
这有助于我思考细节
a biblical text but when it comes to all
圣经的文字，但是当 涉及到所有
kinds of other things I can think
我能想到的其他事情
sometimes in too much detail just ask my
有时太详细了，请问我的
wife it was very helpful for me as I've
老婆，对我来说 非常有帮助
tried to learn my wife to realize she
试图学习我的妻子认识她
thinks differently than I do
我的想法不同于我
her brain processes life differently
她的大脑处理生活方式不同
than the way my brain processes life
而不是我的大脑处理生活的方式
that's kind of a for what it's worth
这是一种值得的东西
statement just to help you learn to be
声明只是为了帮助你学习
patient with other people and learn to
与其他人一起耐心并学习
dwell with your wife in an understanding
和你的妻子一起理解
way learning to try to understand the
学习尝试理解的方式
way she thinks her unique get giftedness
她认为她的独特之处得到了天赋
her unique personality etc under B
B下她独特的个性等
number 2 study your wife continuously
2号继续研究你的妻子
we're going on 31 years of marriage and
我们要结婚31年了
I'm still learning things about my wife
我还在学习关于我妻子的事情
I think that that's part of the blessing
我认为这是 祝福 的一部分
instead of letting that be a frustration
而不是让那是一种挫败感
that can be a great blessing that you
这对你来说是一件很棒的祝福
never exhaust who this person is part of
永远不要穷尽这个人是谁的一部分
the unique mystery of marriage is that
婚姻的独特之处在于
you're continuing to grow continuing to
你继续成长继续
understand each other this is number two
彼此了解这是第二位
says the result of doing this your
说这样做的结果你的
prayers are not hindered through the
祈祷不受阻碍
years in my marriage that has been a
在我的婚姻中已经过了多年
highly motivational little phrase
高度激励的小短语
for conflict resolution I need to treat
解决冲突我需要对待
my wife with respect because I take my
我的妻子因为我带走了我的尊重
walk with the Lord seriously and if I am
如果我是真的，请认真对待主
not respecting her and treating her the
不尊重她，也不尊重她
way that I need to be treating her the
我需要对待她的方式
Lord says my prayers can be hindered now
主说我的祈祷现在可能受到阻碍
what's behind that theologically just
神学的背后是什么
think about what's behind that for a
考虑一下背后的原因
moment that tells me that our God is a
那一刻告诉我，我们的上帝是一个
highly relational God he cares so much
高度关系的上帝，他非常关心
about the way we treat each other that
关于方式，我们对待对方说
if our relationships with each other are
如果我们彼此的关系是
not the way they're supposed to be our
不是他们应该成为我们的方式
relationship with him is not going to be
与他的关系不会是
the way that it's supposed to be another
它应该是另一种方式
verse that reinforces that is Matthew
加强这一点的诗句是马修
chapter 5 that says if you're going to
第5章说，如果你要去
offer your gift at the altar and you
在祭坛上和你一起献上你的礼物
realize that your brother has something
意识到你的兄弟有所作为
against you leave your gift at the altar
反对你把你的礼物留在祭坛上
go and be reconciled to your brother
去和你的兄弟和好
then come back and offer your gift that
然后再来献 礼物
tells me that our God is a highly
告诉我，我们的上帝是高度的
relational being God and he cares about
关系是上帝而他关心的
our relationships with each other I
我们彼此的关系 我
don't want my prayers hindered so I need
我不希望我的祈祷受到阻碍所以我需要
to be constantly working on my attitude
不断努力的态度
and my relationship with my wife the
和我与妻子的关系
effect of this is your wife's problem is
这是你老婆的问题所在
your problem if it's important to her it
你的问题，如果它对她很重要
needs to be important to you as well now
需要对你很重要，以及现在
at this point it would be good to just
在这一点上，这将是好事
introduce this idea that and some ladies
介绍这个想法和一些女士
may be sitting there are some of your
可能坐在那里有一些你的
counsel leaves may go well I just don't
律师离开可能会顺利，我只是没有
feel comfortable sharing it is not safe
感觉舒服分享它并不安全
in our home to talk well that's a
在我们家里好好谈谈这是一个
obviously a really important thing to
显然是非常重要的事情
talk about why is it not safe to talk
谈谈为什么谈话不安全
what is it about the environment in our
是什么样的环境下我们的
home that makes it unsafe to talk so if
如果，如此说话的家庭，这是不安全的
it's unsafe to talk the first thing that
谈论第一件事是不安全的
you need to talk about is why it's
你需要谈论的是它的原因
unsafe to talk just the first step very
非常不安全，只是第一步
strategic thing about what can we do to
关于我们能做些什么的战略性事情
make it a safe environment for us to
让它成为一个安全的环境
both be able to share what's going on in
两者都能分享正在发生的事情
our lives what I've done with counsel
我的生活与律师所做的一切
ease and I've done this with my wife
我和妻子一起做了这件事
from time to time
时
especially with council leaves I've
尤其是理事会离开我
asked this question is there anything
问这个问题有什么
that I'm doing that makes it feel unsafe
我这样做会让人觉得不安全
for you to be able to talk freely with
你是能够 与自由交谈
me as the councillor and here's what I
我作为议员，这就是我
heard one time from a councillor I feel
我觉得有一次是从议员那里听到的
like or counsel II I feel like you're
喜欢或建议我觉得你是
the theological police and every time I
神学警察和我每次
say anything and I express any ideas
说什么，我表达任何想法
about the Bible
关于圣经
you're jumping all over me to correct my
你在我身边跳来纠正我的
bad theology and I thought wow that was
坏神学，我觉得哇
really good for me to hear what do I
我真的很高兴能听到我的意见
need how can I work on this as a
我需要如何处理这个问题
counselor so that it's safe for my
辅导员所以，它的安全我
counsel Lee to talk but yet build the
律师李谈，但尚未建立
type of relationship with the person so
与人如此关系的类型
that I can then speak truth back to them
然后 ， 我可以向他们说实话
in love I think that that would also be
恋爱中我认为那也是
an important thing for a husband and
对丈夫来说很重要
wife to talk about is there anything
老婆谈什么都有
that I'm doing that makes it feel unsafe
我这样做会让人觉得不安全
for you to be able to talk with me the
你能够 与我交谈
last point a christ-like husband is a
最后一点， 一个基督般的丈夫是一个
servant leader christ-like husband is a
仆人领袖基督般的丈夫是一个
servant leader I'd like to go back to
仆人领袖我想回去
the mark 10 passage where we started off
我们开始的标记10通道
so let's go back to mark 10 you have in
让我们回到10标记你有
your notes Matthew 20 it's a parallel
你的笔记马太福音20是平行的
passage I actually like the mark 10
我真的喜欢马克10
passage better and then in the notes we
通过更好，然后在笔记中我们
have some of the implications of being a
有一些影响成为一个
servant leader so what have we seen so
仆人领袖所以我们看到了什么
far it's a christ-like lover a learner
远远不是一个像基督一样的爱人学习者
and a servant leader biblical manhood is
和仆人的领袖是圣经的男子气概
about leading loving leadership lovingly
关于领导爱心领导的爱心
providing and lovingly protecting in
提供和亲切保护
essence it's the idea of being a
本质上是一个想法
shepherd your family is your flock and
牧养你的家人就是你的羊群
your shepherding your flock a servant
你牧养你的羊群仆人
leader I'm gonna start reading with
领导我将开始阅读
verse 40 just to pick up a little bit of
第40节只是为了拿起一点点
the context and the Lord is saying to
上下文和神的话语，并
back to his disciples who are fighting
回到他们正在战斗的弟子身边
over positions of authority but to sit
在权威的位置，但坐下来
on my right and on my left that's not
在我的右边和左边那不是
mine to give but it's for those who
我要给，但这是给那些谁
for whom it has been prepared and
对谁准备好了
hearing this the ten began to feel
听到这十个开始感觉到了
indignant towards James and John and
对詹姆斯和约翰的愤怒
calling them to himself jesus said to
耶稣称他们为自己
them you know that those who are
他们你知道那些人
recognized as rulers of the Gentiles
被承认为外邦人的统治者
lord it over them so ungodly leadership
领导他们如此不敬虔的领导
is about lording it's about domineering
关于它是关于霸气的
and they're great men exercise authority
他们是伟大的人行使权力
there's a difference
有区别
men and again we need to teach this to
男人们又一次我们需要教导这个
the men we're mentoring between being
我们正在指导的男人
authoritative and authoritarian many men
权威和专制的许多人
can be domineering authoritarian verse
可以是霸气专制的诗歌
43 but it's not so among you but whoever
43但你不是这样， 而是谁
wishes to become great among you shall
希望在你们中间变得伟大
be your servant
做你的仆人
whoever wishes to be first among you
谁愿意成为你的第一人
shall be slave of all for even the Son
即使是儿子，也应成为所有人的奴隶
of man did not come to be served but to
男人没有来服务但是
serve and to give his life a ransom for
发球和给他的生活赎金
many
许多
number one - for under the dictatorship
第一- 在独裁统治下
idea the idea is that is trying to we're
这个想法是我们想要的
trying to capture the idea that these
试图捕捉的想法，这些
are not things that I'm demanding if a
事情并不是我要求很高，如果
wife wants to do these things and
妻子想去做这些事情和
obviously she would want to follow her
显然她会想跟着她
husband's leadership she would want to
她希望丈夫的领导能力
make her Holman than the home a nice
让她的霍尔曼比家里的好
place to live she would want to listen
住的地方，她会想要 听
to her husband's opinion in preference
对她丈夫的偏好
but I am NOT to be a domineering leader
但我不是一个霸气的领导者
in my home forcing these things on the
在我的家里强迫这些东西
people that I'm trying to lead it
人们， 我正试图领导它
doesn't mean making all the decisions
并不意味着做出所有决定
you can read all the sub points there it
你可以阅读那里的所有子点
obviously doesn't mean following your
显然并不意味着跟随你
wife someone has to be the leader in the
妻子有人必须成为领导者
home and look at point-c they're number
回家看看他们的数字
one under following your wife another
一个跟着你的妻子另一个
controversial passage says this I want
有争议的段落说我想要的
you to understand that Christ is the
你要明白基督就是这样
head of every man the man is the head of
每个人的男子头部的头
a woman and God is the head of Christ
一个女人，上帝是基督的头
that's a really controversial passage
这是一个非常有争议的段落
a man ought to not have his head covered
一个人应该不会有蒙着头
since he's the image and glory of God
因为他 是上帝的形象和荣耀
but the woman is the glory of man for
但女人是 男人的 荣耀
man does not originate for woman but
男人不是为女人而来
woman from man for indeed man was not
确实是男人的男人不是
created for woman's sake but woman for
为了女人而创造，但女人为
man's sake I just I wanted to read that
男人的缘故我只是想读一读
just to emphasize again that this is not
只是再次强调这不是
about superiority and inferiority it's
关于优越性和自卑感
about function in the home and if you
关于在家里的功能，如果你
have more questions about that please
对此有更多疑问
get that book recovering biblical
让那本书恢复圣经
manhood and womanhood
男人和女人
what is this godly leadership now
什么是现在这位虔诚的领导
instead of reading all of these points
而不是阅读所有这些点
what I want to do is I'm gonna switch to
我想做的是我要转向
10 points that John Piper makes about
John Piper提出的10分
what is does it mean to be a biblical
成为一个圣经是什么意思
leader and these come from that book
领导者和这些来自那本书
biblical recovering biblical manhood and
圣经恢复圣经的男子气概和
womanhood Lots there in the notes that
女人气在那里有很多笔记
you can look at it's really easy for us
你可以看看它对我们来说真的很容易
men to say okay yes I want to be the
男人说好的我是想成为的
servant of my home here's a statement I
我家的仆人在这里发表声明
heard years ago early in pastoral
几年前早些时候在田园里听说过
ministry that I found very convicting
我发现非常有罪的事工
because I would say to you I want to be
因为我想对你说我想成为
a servant as a pastor and the speaker
作为牧师和演讲者的仆人
said this you can tell a real servant by
说这个你可以告诉一个真正的仆人
how he acts when he's treated like one
当他被当作一个人对待时，他的行为如何
just two on it and think about it a
短短两年就可以了，想想它
little bit here's nine points about what
这里有点关于什么的九点
is a leader a servant leader John Piper
是仆人领袖约翰派珀的领导者
says this mature masculinity and I can
说这种成熟的阳刚之气我能做到
make this available to you if you'd like
使此提供给你，如果你想
it mature masculinity expresses itself
它成熟的男性气质表达自己
not in a demand to be served but in the
不是在需求提供服务，但在
strength to serve and to sacrifice for
实力，为和牺牲
the good of a woman number two mature
二号女人的好 成熟
masculinity does not assume the
男性气质不承担
authority of Christ over woman but
基督对女人的权威，但是
advocates it she has a lord in other
提倡她在其他方面有一个领主
words you're not her Lord she has a lord
你不是她的话，她有一个领主
and you're trying to
和你想
help her follow her Lord number three
帮助她跟随她的主三号
mature masculinity does not presume
成熟的男子气概并不是假设的
superiority but mobilizes the strengths
优势但调动优势
of others that's just good managing good
其他那些善于管理好的人
shepherding number for mature
成熟的牧羊号码
masculinity does not have to initiate
男性气质不必启动
every action but does feel the
每一个行动， 但确实感受到了
responsibility to provide a general
负责提供一个通用
pattern of initiative number five
第五项倡议模式
mature masculinity accepts the burden of
成熟的男子气概接受了负担
the final say in disagreements between a
最后的说法是在a之间的分歧
husband and wife but does not presume to
丈夫和妻子，但不认为
use it in every instance number six
在每个第六个实例中使用它
mature masculinity expresses its
成熟的男性气质表达了它
leadership in romantic sexual relations
浪漫性关系中的领导力
by communicating an aura of strong but
通过传达强大的光环但是
tender pursuit seven mature masculinity
温柔的追求七成熟的阳刚之气
expresses itself in a family by taking
通过服用在一个家庭中表达自己
the initiative we're hearing a lot about
我们听到很多关于这个的倡议
initiative in disciplining the children
训练孩子的主动性
when both parents are present and a
当父母双方都存在和
family standard has been broken
家庭标准已被打破
number eight mature masculinity is
八号成熟男性气质是
sensitive to cultural expressions of
对文化表达敏感
masculinity and adapts to them where no
男子气概，并适应他们没有
sin is involved in order to communicate
为了交流，涉及到罪
to a woman that a man would like to
一个女人，一个男人想
relate not in any aggressive or
不涉及任何侵略性或
perverted away but with maturity and
变态走，但与成熟，
dignity as a man and then lastly mature
尊严作为一个男人，然后最后成熟
masculinity recognizes that the call to
阳刚承认调用
leadership is a call to repentance and
领导是呼吁悔改和
humility and risk risk-taking may the
谦虚和风险冒险可能是
Lord help us develop what it truly means
主帮助我们发展它真正的意义
to be biblical men who are Shepherds
成为圣经的牧羊人
that know how to lead provide for and
知道如何领导和提供
protect that know what it means to be a
保护那知道它意味着什么
lover a learner and a servant leader
爱学习者和仆人领袖
you
您